We are going to be learning how to manage domain names in microsoft Trisses 5
are being center. So we will create a free turnance with microsoft Trisses 5
E5 or E3. You're going to have a default domain name with the domain name which you choose
and then it's going to be with the domain name then then dot on microsoft.com.
So if I go to settings in microsoft Trisses 5 at main center and I go to domains.
Here you can see we have the domain called kel global dot on microsoft.com.
And that is the default domain name which was actually assigned to me when I created this free turnance.
But you have two options. For example, to add a domain name you already purchased or to buy a domain name.
For example, I want to buy domain name. I also have a new domain. I can just click buy domain.
And you can see it says, well first of all, for you to buy domain name you need to upgrade your trial.
Before you come by domain name you need to upgrade your trial plan. Then you can then connect new domains in this service including your subscription.
But let's close that. Let's see, we already have it domain. And we want to add that domain to our domain.
So let's now add click add a domain. So by clicking add a domain for example, I'm just going to add let me just add the kel global dot com.
So kel global dot com. I'm the owner of that domain. And for example, I want to use this domain as my default domain.
And which of course, I want to be able to sync this domain to my own premises environment where my user should be able to use the kel global dot com to log into Microsoft 365 instead of using the dot on Microsoft dot com.
So what I need to do right now is a following. I will need to just select use this domain.
So by selecting use this domain, this is what it's going to happen. You're going to say say you need to verify if you are the owner of that domain because you just can add into main to Microsoft 365 admin center.
I just hope that you have been verified. Of course, now you can see since added test record to the domain DNS record.
If you can add a test record, I don't MS record to the domain DNS record or a test file to the domain websites. So these are the different options you have given my Microsoft.
I'm very afraid that you are the owner of that domain name. So what we need to do, for example, I can't select the first choice and then click OK.
So it's going to give me a test for here. You can see it's going to give me the test name and a test value also at the time to leave. So what you need to do is just to copy this value.
Go to your domain provider and then login to your domain where I provide that and then add this test value to your to your record.
But I didn't instead test out your record. Then you need to click verify by clicking verify if everything goes well. Then it will actually ask you to add some other record.
For example, to be able to use your email address to be able to use your to use Microsoft Intune. It's going to give you some other record which you're going to add and then verify that you are the right owner of that domain.
Well, this time careful about the website or ideas is that I want to add all these tests record to that domain then my email address may not be functioning anymore and my website may not be falling in the way it's supposed to be.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just showing you this to show you how to actually add and start to mean to your Microsoft 365 admin center then you should be able to use that domain as your default domain.
Click verify then you should be able to connect to the main and then click finish.